Guide to the Alfred Hulse Brooks Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs by Other Photographers, 1892-1936; Series II; 1.75
  - Photographs by Identified Photographers
    - Miller, N. B. and Charles Haskins Townsend, 1895 September 7 (Box 10, Folder 914-915)
      Charles Haskins Townsend (1859-1944) was an American zoologist. From 1897 to 1902 he served as the chief of the fisheries division of the United States Fish Commission. From 1902 to 1937, he served as director of the New York Aquarium at Castle Garden.
      Views created by the partnership of Miller and Townsend of a glacier, probably the Hubbard Glacier in Yakutat Bay, from the USS Albatross.
    - Morse, Edward C., circa 1900 (Box 10, Folder 916)
      Edward C. Morse (born 1872) was a journalist and mine superintendent at the Sea Level Mine on Revillagigedo Island.
      Image depicts the Sea Level Mine during its construction on Revillagigedo Island.
    - Nowell, Frank H., circa 1905-1910 (Box 10, Folder 917-923)
      Frank H. Nowell (1864-1950) was a photographer in Nome, Alaska, and Seattle, Washington.
      Images near Nome include the operations Center Creek Mining Company, the Gertrude Mine, the Wild Goose Company. Several images show dredges of the Three Friends Mining Company in the Solomon River, as well as Dredge No.1 (Wisconsin) of Bursik and Co. in the Snake River.
    - Pedersen, Louis H., 1911-1912 (Box 10, Folder 924-925)
      Louis H. Pedersen (born 1867) was a clergyman for churches in Douglas, 1901-1905; Seward, 1905-1913; and Skagway, 1913. He also made postcard photographs during the early twentieth century. His sons Frederick Louis Pedersen (born 1893) and Ralph Martin Pedersen (born 1894) operated the Pedersen Brothers studio in Skagway, which sold photographic postcards.
      Images consist of a view of USS Maryland in Resurrection Bay; and a montage of five photos advertising economic opportunities in Knik sponsored by the Knik Commercial Club.
      - Oversize group portrait, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 926)
        Party that accompanied Walter Lowrie Fisher, Secretary of the Interior, during his tour of Alaska, which includes Alfred Hulse Brooks and Alaskan Governor Walter Eli Clark
    - Reeth, Herman Werner, 1920 (Box 10, Folder 927-930)
      Herman Werner Reeth (born 1864) was an author, inventor, and miner in Bethel
      Images near Bethel and on the Kisaralik River, which include views of the Golden Gate Falls and hydraulic mining.
    - Reid, Harry Fielding, 1892 (Box 10, Folder 931-934)
      Harry Fielding Reid (1859-1944) was a geologist known for his contributions in the fields of seismology and glaciology.
      Views of Charpentier Glacier and the Hugh Miller Inlet.
    - Schneider, William, circa 1919 (Box 10, Folder 935-939)
      William Schneider was a partner in Schneider Bros., a mining operation on Little Creek, a tributary to the Innoko River.
      Images depict hydraulic mining.
    - Shade, Orie Irving, or Charles A. Shade, 1914-1917 (Box 10, Folder 940)
      Orie Irving Shade (1877-1963) and Charles A. Shade (born 1887) were brothers living in Tanana, circa 1915-1920. The former managed a general store in Tanana in 1930, and the latter served in World War I and later worked as a postal carrier in Nenena.
      Time lapse photograph of Sun taken at intervals of twenty minutes during a Winter Solstice in Tanana.
    - Stuck, Hudson, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 941-945)
      Hudson Stuck (1863-1920) was an archdeacon with the Protestant Episcopal Church in Fort Yukon. Stuck and Harry P. Karstens led the first expedition that successfully climbed the South Summit of Mount McKinley in June 1913.
      Images include a group portrait of Native Americans at Lake Minchumina, a dog sled en route between Cos Jacket and Lake Minchumina, and landscape views.
    - Thwaites, John Edward, circa 1912 (Box 10, Folder 946-950)
      John Edward Thwaites (1863-1940) was an amateur photographer and a clerk for the Railway Mail Service. From 1905 to 1912, he lived on the mailboat steamer Dora owned by the Northwestern Steamship Company and traveled the route from Valdez to Unalaska delivering mail to the coastal communities.
      Images include a United States Navy ship near the Taku Glacier in the Taku Inlet, views of Kodiak from the water, a cannery ship in Bristol Bay, and the steamer Dora.
    - Tourtellotte, Arch James, 1935 November-1936 (Box 10, Folder 951-955)
      Arch James Tourtellotte (1878-1959) was an accountant in Portland, Oregon.
      Images include mining operations of Klery Placers, Inc., on Klery Creek and mining operations on Squirrel Creek.
    - Townsend, Calvin F., circa 1915 (Box 10, Folder 956-957)
      Calvin F. Townsend was a game warden with the United States Bureau of Fisheries and based in Fairbanks from 1913 to 1918.
      Images of a gray fox at the Kayak Island Fox Ranch.
    - Tweet, Edgar Phillip, 1926 September (Box 10, Folder 958)
      Edgar Phillip Tweet (born 1900) was a miner in Teller.
    - United States Forest Service, 1915 December 8 (Box 10, Folder 959)
      View of two men aboard the agency boat, Ranger I, at a Sitka dock on Silver Bay.
    - United States Navy Alaska Aerial Survey Expedition, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 960-962)
      United States Navy Alaska Aerial Survey Expedition took place in 1926 and 1929 to acquire vertical images for creating topographic maps.
      Images include aerial views of Ketchikan, a glacier, and a forest.
    - Valentine & Sons, circa 1920 (Box 10, Folder 963-966)
      Valentine & Sons was a printing company established in 1851 by James Valentine (1814-1879) in Dundee, Scotland. The firm was a pioneer in the postcard industry.
      Postcard views of the exhibits at the Museum of the Geological Survey of Canada in the Victoria Memorial Museum Building in Ottawa, Ontario.
    - Western Alaska Construction Company, 1903 (Box 10, Folder 967-969)
      Western Alaska Construction Company was established in Chicago, circa 1903. It was the lead contractor in building the Council City and Solomon River Railroad.
      Images of the general offices of the company in Dickson and related to the construction of the Council City and Solomon River Railroad.
    - Winter & Pond, circa 1893-1920 (Box 10, Folder 970-981)
      Winter & Pond was a photography studio of Lloyd Valentine Winter (1866-1945) and Edwin Percy Pond (1872-1943) in Juneau, 1893-1943.
      Images of mining operations that include the Alaska Treadwell Gold Mining Company on Douglas Island; the Alaska Juneau Mine at Silver Bow Basin; the Eagle River Mining Company at Amalga; the Ebner Gold Mining Company in Juneau; the Ebner Gold Mines Company and Humboldt Mining Company at Gold Creek; the Mellen Mining Company and the Kensington Mining Company at Berners Bay; and the Porcupine Mining Company at Porcupine River. A view hydraulic mining in the Silver Bow Basin includes Edwin Percy Pond with a camera.
    - Wolfe, Frank Eddy, 1905-1906 (Box 11, Folder 982-989)
      Frank Eddy Wolfe (born 1869) was born in Ohio and operated a photograph studio in Dawson City, Yukon. In 1924, he lived in Los Angeles, California.
      Images of mining operations in the Yukon, including Bonanza Creek, Dominion Creek, Eldorado Creek, and Hunker Creek.
  - Photographs by Unidentified Photographers
    - Locations
      - Anchorage, circa 1915 (Box 11, Folder 990)
        Mill in the foreground and tent city in the distance.
      - Chichagof Island, circa 1917 (Box 11, Folder 991)
        Man with a portable testing mill at the Jumbo Claim on the west side of Klag Bay.
      - Fort Liscum, circa 1915 (Box 11, Folder 992)
      - Georgetown, Ohio, and three men at Buttermilk Falls, circa 1907 (Box 11, Folder 993)
      - Iditarod, circa 1910 (Box 11, Folder 994-995)
      - Ketchikan and the steamship City of Seattle in dry dock., 1912 August 15 (Box 11, Folder 996)
      - Kodiak Island, and the steamship Admiral Sampson, circa 1910 (Box 11, Folder 997)
      - Latouche Island, circa 1910-1920 (Box 11, Folder 998-999)
        Views of the waterfront and of the motorship Kennecott.
      - Otter Creek, 1910 July 5 (Box 11, Folder 1000)
      - Prince William Sound and Shoup Glacier, circa 1910 (Box 11, Folder 1001)
      - Seward, circa 1915 (Box 11, Folder 1002-1003)
        Group around an open railcar and a display of eight bear skins.
      - Skeena River, British Columbia, and the steamship Inlander, circa 1910-1912 (Box 11, Folder 1004-1005)
      - Valdez, circa 1915 (Box 11, Folder 1006)
    - Portraits
      - Child wearing a parka and pulling a sled, circa 1915 (Box 11, Folder 1007)
      - Dog in a yard, circa 1915 (Box 11, Folder 1008)
  - Panoramas
    - Kinne, Albert Barnes, 1903 (Box 12, Folder 1009)
      Albert Barnes Kinne (1853-1925) operated photography studios in San Francisco, Nome, and Council. He was also a partner with Beverly B. Dobbs in their Nome studio, Dobbs & Kinne, 1903-1905.
      Panoramic view of a freight scow with sail on the Neukluk River.
    - McRae Brothers Limited, circa 1920 (Box 12, Folder 1010-1011)
      Images in the vicinity of British Columbia include a view from Mount Oldfield of Digby Island and a view of the Zanardi River Bridge.
    - Unidentified photographers
      - Columbia River, Oregon and Washington, circa 1915 (Box 12, Folder 1012)
      - Cordova and Eyak Lake, circa 1907-1908 (Box 12, Folder 1013-1014)
      - Dawson City, Yukon, circa 1900 (Box 12, Folder 1015-1017)
      - Katalla, circa 1907-1908 (Box 12, Folder 1018)
      - Takotna, circa 1910 (Box 12, Folder 1019)
      - Unidentified locations
        - Panoramas of a bay and valley, circa 1900-1907 November 15 (Box 12, Folder 1020-1021)
        - Men and supplies on a river barge pulled by a horse, circa 1910 (Box 12, Folder 1022)
        - Ridgeline of a mountain range and a man posed prone on the ridge of a mountain, circa 1940 (Box 12, Folder 1023-1024)